Brown Family Papers, 1825-1912, 1965 (Bulk 1850-1894)
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Brown Family Papers, 1825-1912, 1965 (Bulk 1850-1894)
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1990-011
1 box; 0.5 cu. ft.
The collection consists of receipts, bills, Promissory notes, tax notes, letters, and other various papers created between 1825 and 1912 by members of the Brown, and other related families.
Brown family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Brown Family Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1990. Additional materials were donated in 1994.
Biographical Information
James Cartmill Brown was born in 1828. Brown was a farmer in Montgomery County, Virginia. About 1851, he married Ann Elizabeth Thomas (b. abt. 1831). They had at least six children: Mellie (Mollie?) (b. abt. 1854), John C. (b. abt. 1857), D. Howe (b. abt. 1859), Florence E. (b. abt. 1864), Robert L. (b. abt. 1867), and James M. (b. abt. 1872). Brown died in 1913.
Thomas Brown was probably James Cartmill Brown's brother, but it is unclear if this is Thomas W. or Thomas M. (both are mentioned in the collection). A number of items relate to Annie E. Barnett, but her connection to the family is unknown.
Scope and Content
The Brown Family Papers contain the papers of James Cartmill Brown (1828-1913), a landowner of a farm on the north fork of the Roanoke River in Montgomery County, Virginia. The materials consist of receipts, bills, Promissory notes, tax notes, letters, and other various papers created between 1825 and 1912, with the bulk of the collection from 1850 to 1894, by members of the Brown family, as they purchased services and goods from business people in their community. The collection includes receipts from the services of Dr. Harvey (Harvy) Black of Blacksburg, and genealogical material of the Brown lineage created in 1965.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged folders by year. Documents are filed based on the year of creation, rather than payment, court, or other dates.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Blacksburg (Va.); Civil War; Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Montgomery County (Va.); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865
Contents List
- (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Bill for goods (flour, salt, coffee, sugar) bought by Thos. Brown. Paid for by John and Seth Halsey, November 18, 1825.
- (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Summons for John Brown to appear before the Judge of the Circuit Court of Botetourt Co., May 23, 1839.
- (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Bill for 6 bushels of corn paid to David Kent, Jr., November 3, 184?.
  - Note from C.F. Whitescarver to Thomas Brown asking him to come to "Pleasant Green"" at 1 p.m. next day, January 21, 1940.
  - Bill to Thomas Brown from Baldwin & Gibboney for goods purchased, 1840.
  - Bill to Thomas Brown from D. Baldwin for goods purchased between July and November, 1840.
- (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Invitation to a ball at Union Hotel in Salem on Friday, February 22, 1848.
  - To Miss Ann E. Barnett, Montgomery Co., from "Managers" David Shanks, W.H. Roberts, A.S. Pitzen, W.W. Williams, H.E. Blair, Jas. W. Shields, Jas. Wade, Jas. S. Taylor, Jas. C. Taylor, and Alex Whitton, February 11, 1848.
- (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Tax receipt (2 tithes and road tax) owed by Henry Craig but paid by James Brown, 1849.
  - Promissory note (no names) for $219.58, due February 1, 1850, February 17, 1849.
- (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Coal bill from William Dowdy to John Brown, 185?.
  - Tailoring bill from S.J. Beatty to John Brown, June 27, 1850.
  - Bill to John Brown, April 4, 1850.
- (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Bill from Wm. Obenshain & Co. for clothing and household goods purchased in 1851, November 16, 1851.
  - Receipt to John Brown for recording a deed for Thos. Brown by R.D. Montague, November 1851.
  - Bill for goods bought in 1851 and 1852 by James C. Brown from Wm. Thomas, 1851.
  - Bill dated Catawba, Va., 1851, from D.G. Thomas to James Brown, listing the following names, with small sums of money after each one: Vandagrift, George Bradley, Marke Vandagrift, John Vandagrift, Charles Old, Griffin Vandagrift, G. Leonard, and Mrs. Parrish, 1851.
  - Tailoring bill from S. J. Beatty to Thomas Brown, Snr., January 31, 1852.
  - Bill for leather goods to Wash Smith from Jas. Brown, January 1851.
  - Bill from M.E. Woolwine to James C. Brown for leather goods, March 13, 1853.
- (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Receipt for $76.70 paid by J. Brown to Jesse Hall, September 23, 1852.
  - Bill from Thos. W. Jones to Brown & Ross for shoemaking materials, 1852.
  - Bill from Jas. Brown to Henry Kieffer for leather, 1852.
  - Promissory note of James Craig to James C. Brown, September 7, 1852.
  - Leather bill dated December 29, 1852, through January 25, 1855, from J.C. Hall to James C. Brown, 1852.
- (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Bill for three month's work from William T. Ross to James C. Brown, 1853.
  - Letter from J.N. Pepper from Christiansburg, Montgomery, Virginia, to "Dear Cousin" (Ann E. Barnett), November 23, 1853.
  - Cobbler's bill to James C. Brown; through 1854, 1853.
  - Cobbler's bill from William Collins to James C. Brown, August 22, 1853.
  - Bill from James C. Brown to William Keiffer, December 26, 1853.
  - Bill from James C. Brown to Richard Phillips for leather goods, August-December 1853.
  - Note from Capt. Kent to Miss Barnett, February 1, 1853.
  - Carpenter's bill for house, December 26, 1853.
  - Bill from Hy N. Ekiss to James Brown for services rendered, 1853.
  - Promissory note from William Collins to James C. Brown, August 22, 1853.
  - Eight Promissory notes from M.E. Woolwine, William Keffer, and Jas. Brown, 1853.
  - Bill for items bought in 1851 and 1852 from J.R. Phillips & Co., including a Panama hat, shoe thread, a silver pencil, and a pair of buck gloves; paid March 12, 1853.
  - Bill from M.E. Woolwine to James C. Brown for items purchased in 1853 and 1854, including a buggy whip, a snaffle bridle, and a trunk strap, 1853.
  - Receipt for $3.77 paid by William Kiffe to Brown and Ross, July 5, 1853.
  - Promissory note from M.E. Woolwine to pay $76.26 to James C. Brown, 1853.
- (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Bill for a subscription of the Virginia Recorder for James C. Brown, 1854.
  - Two bills from Murrell & Stratton to John Brown for such items as herring and whiskey, May 26, 1854.
  - Bill from McDonald's store to James C. Brown for nails, shovel, shoes, and nutmeg, 1854.
  - Promissory note from William Bordin to James Brown for $24.63, December 8, 1854.
  - Lumber bill from D. Buck to James Brown for flooring, planking, rafters, and boards, 1854.
  - Bill to William Buber from J.C. Brown for boots and bacon, 1854.
  - "Bill of wirk" for carpentry work done for James C. Brown, December 16, 1854.
  - Bill from James M. Evans to James Brown for "1 covered coffin & case," March 17, 1854.
  - From the Sheriff of Montgomery County, Virginia, to James C. Brown, to appear before the Circuit Court on charges of owing Giles S. Thomas $104.91, December 5, 1854.
  - Letter from D.H. Hoge to John Brown regarding a slave named Jinny, October 15, 1854.
  - Note regarding a bond of $50.39 received by J.C. Brown for Robert Elim, April 21, 1854.
  - Invitation for a party at Yellow Springs on August 24, 1854, from managers C.F.M. Garnett, Sam'l J. Booker, J.R. M'Daniel, E.G. Wall, Wm. M. Cook, John F. Terry, George W. Shanks, Jubal A. Early, S.A. M'Conkey, R.H. Mosby, J.W. Shields, and R.C. Trigg,1854.
  - Receipt from Giles S. Thomas for two bonds of James C. Brown to replace two that were "lost or mislaid," November 21, 1854.
  - Promissory note to Peter Crumpecker owing $30.00 to James Brown, August 24, 1854.
  - Promissory note to James W. Dent from James Brown to pay $27.45, September 1, 1854.
  - Note from William Allen asking James Brown to pay George Keister $40.00 "in tithe [i.e. railroad ties] at the market price," October 13, 1854.
  - Promissory note from James C. Brown to D.G. Thomas to pay $48.55, November 1, 1854.
  - Promissory note from James Brown promising to pay Keller & Jordan $19.00, November 5, 1854.
  - Note from Wm. P. Baker asking James Brown to pay Jonas Henderson $54.67, November 18, 1854.
  - Promissory note from James Brown (?) to pay Evins & Gish $198.93, December 20, 1854.
  - Note from Floyd Smith for James Brown to pay taxes for Sam Gordon, 1854.
  - Promissory note to Edwin J. Amis from James Brown to pay $8.00, July 11, 1854.
  - Promissory note from James Brown to Giles Barnett to pay $20.00, May 26, 1854.
  - Promissory note to Stanger & Linkous from James C. Brown to pay $8.13, April 24, 1854.
  - Promissory note to James Robinson from James Brown (?) to pay $7.54, April 15, 1854.
  - Letter to James Brown from Acrum(?) + W. Clanahan to pay for tanners oil and linseed oil purchased from them, March 24, 1854.
  - Receipt from A.E. Early to James Brown for $15.00 paid in full, January 31, 1854.
  - Manuscript copy of a bill of work, 1854.
  - Promissory note to William J. Ross from James Brown (?) to pay $19.50, January 14, 1854.
  - Promissory note to William Ross from James Brown to pay $9.00, January 7, 1854.
  - Receipt from Thos. W. Jones to James C. Brown for payment due, January 3, 1854.
  - Receipt from Tobias Oliver for $77.25 to unknown, June 13, 1854.
- (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Bill from James C. Brown to D.H. & J. F. Hoge "to fee in case of his father's will," November 1855.
  - Bill to Steven Solimon from Jas. C. Brown regarding a harness, January 20, 1855.
  - Bill for goods bought in 1855 from A.M. Luster by James C. Brown, January 14, 1855.
  - Bill for goods bought from G.W. Gish by James C. Brown, January 5, 1855.
  - Bill for hogs and hides bought from William Doosing by James Brown, February 19, 1855.
  - Bill for subscription to the Herald, 1855.
  - Note and bill from Younger and Smith to Jas. C. Brown for whiskey, January 27, 1855.
  - Farmer's Bank of Virginia note for payment of $285 from James C. Brown to A.W. Luster, December 12, 1855.
  - General merchandise bill from A.W. Luster at McDonald's Mill, to James C. Brown, 1855.
  - Note and bill for molasses and whiskey bought by James C. Brown from Younger & Smith in Lynchburg, Virginia, September 5, 1855.
  - Receipt for clothes bought in 1855 by James C. Brown from Earhart & Wilson, February 20, 1855.
  - Bill from Samuel Bossick to James C. Brown for odd jobs, September 13, 1855.
  - Bill from Jas. Brown to Wm. Johnston for shoemaking materials, 1855.
  - Bill from Younger & Smith to James C. Brown for whiskey, molasses, herring, and bags bought in 1855 and 1856, March 20, 1858.
  - Bill from John Keister to James C. Brown for oil, tanyard, a calf, and hogs, 1855.
  - Note from John Brown to Mr. Cagy asking him to let Thomas Brown have "2 barrels of flower," April 5, 1855.
  - Bill from Wm. H. Peck to James C. Brown for 600 bags of plaster, June 6, 1855.
  - General merchandise bill from J.M. & G.D. Thomas to James C. Brown, 1855.
  - Bill from Mr. Samuel J. Beedy to James C. Brown for shoe materials, January 25, 1855.
  - Bill from Samuel Gordon to James Brown to pay him $3.00, October 6, 1855.
  - Promissory note to A.W. Luster to pay Jas. C. Brown $176.47, September 28, 1855.
  - Receipt for $3.00 from Jas. Brown to Wm. T. Bales, September 12, 1855.
  - Promissory note to Mary Henderson from James Brown for $27.74, August 15, 1855.
  - Receipt from James M. Evans to Jas. Brown for $5.00, July 21, 1855.
  - Promissory note from James C. Brown to A.W. Luster for $36.75, June 13, 1855.
  - Promissory note from James C. Brown to W. Doosing for $11.62, February 19, 1855.
  - Promissory note from J.M. & G.D. Thomas to James Brown for $212.67, January 15, 1855.
  - Promissory note from James Brown to Samuel Lester for $18.00, December 24, 1855.
  - Receipt for goods bought by unknown from unknown, August 16, 1855.
  - Receipt for goods bought from Samuel Lester by James C. Brown, December 24, 1855.
  - Promissory note from James C. Brown to Henry King for $24.05, May 12, 1855.
- (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Receipt from William B. Charles to James Brown for 100 acres of land, February 8, 1856.
  - Receipt from James Brown to the surveyor of Montgomery County, March 13, 1856.
  - Bill from Lancaster Bane of Blacksburg to John Brown for a hat, plaster, and other items, April 21, 1856.
  - Bill to James C. Brown from E. Wilson for a "Satten vest," May 27, 1856.
  - Bill from A.W. Luster to John Brown for such items as a teapot, hats, a shawl, knives, and spoons, bought at auction, December 25, 1856.
  - Invitation from Mr. & Mrs. Joseph Deyerle of Shawsville to Mr. James Barnett, October 20, 1856.
  - Bill from J.P. Wilson to Mr. J.C. Brown for goods bought, June 7, 1856.
  - Bill from A.H. Shewer to James Brown, April 16, 1856.
  - Receipt from Henry Surface to Jas. C. Brown to settle accounts, February 26, 1856.
  - Bill from A.W. Luster to James Brown for goods bought in 1856 and 1857, February 10, 1856.
  - Bill to M. William Finch from A.W. Luster for goods bought (includes provisions for James Brown), 1856.
  - Doctor bill from Harvy Black to John Brown for services rendered in 1856 and 1857, 1856.
  - Bill from J.W. Brown to James C. Brown for shoe work from 1856 to 1859, March 26, 1860.
  - Receipt from A.W. Luster to James C. Brown for $9.50, March 14, 1856.
  - Group of Promissory notes to James C. Brown (signature torn from all), 1856.
  - Receipt from Jacob All as administrator of James All deceased to James C. Brown for $8.40, August 16, 1856.
  - Notice from the Bank of the Valley of Virginia that a check for $300.00 drawn by A.P. Whitlock, endorsed by Nathl. Burkett, E. McDonald, and Jas. C. Brown, was refused. Signed by Notary Public Haml. W. Shield, October 30, 1856.
  - Bill to James C. Brown for goods purchased at an auction, December 25, 1856.
  - Receipt to Samuel Gordon for his 1856 taxes and tithes, 1856.
  - Obituary clippings for Mrs Mary J. Deyerly of Blacksburg, who died of dropsy, 1856.
- (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Bill from J.T. & T.R. Evans to James Brown for general merchandise purchased from 1857 to 1860, March 18, 1860.
  - Cobbler's bill from Al Craig to Jas. Brown, 1857.
  - Notice from a Notary Public on behalf of Farmer's Bank of Virginia, at Blacksburg, regarding non-payment of a note from J.C. Brown, July 27, 1857.
  - Bill for "2 pair Linnen Pants" from Jno. W. Thomas to Jas. Brown, April 10, 1857.
  - Invitation for a ball given at Thomas Springs on 26 December 1857, from "Managers" W.R. Edmondson, Q.M.G. Kent S.A. M'Conky, H.E. Blair, James Wade, N.M. Ronald, James Dyerle, W. Tucker, G. Price, and C. Barnett, 1857.
  - Bill from A.W. Luster from Jas. C. Brown for cotton, silk, earrings, sugar, etc., January 21, 1857.
  - Bill from G. Keister to James C. Brown for a plow point, 1857.
  - Note from Marion(?) Kent in Edgehill to Anne Barnett inviting her and her brother John to a party on the next day, December 25, 1857.
  - Bill to John Gray from John Brown for wintering his cow for four months, April 27, 1857.
  - Bill from Jno. Obenshain to James C. Brown for calico, ribbon, sugar, cotton, etc., purchased from 1857 to 1859, 1857.
  - Receipt from J.T. Earhart to J.C. Brown for subscription (dues?) to ME Church, 1857.
  - Letter from A.W. Luster to Jas. C. Brown regarding selling a crop and stock (perhaps for auction) and his present state of misery, June 28, 1857.
  - Bill from J.H. Guggenheim for shoes bought from James C. Brown, April 6, 1857.
  - Two bank notices to J.C. Brown from the Office of the Farmers Bank of Virginia, at Blacksburg to pay a delinquent check of A.W. Luster's that Brown had endorsed, February 27 and September 21, 1857.
  - Promissory note from Jas. C. Brown to the Farmers Bank of Virginia, at Blacksburg, to pay $250.00 in ninety days, January 27, 1857.
  - Blank check signed by Jas. C. Brown from the Farmers Bank of Virginia Blacksburg, 1857.
  - Bill from E. Bruitfern(?) to J.C. Brown for $2.97, 1857.
  - Promissory note from Jas. C. Brown to the Farmers Bank of Virginia at Blacksburg for $790.00, June 10, 1857.
  - Bill from Jacob Barnsach to Thos. W. Brown for $17.88 due in July 1857. Paid by James Brown in 1871, July 4, 1857.
  - Bill to James Alls from unknown for $30.00, September 19, 1957.
  - Promissory note from unknown to Geo. Keister for $10.14, January 10, 1857.
  - Receipt from J. Obenshain for $6.00 received from Jas. C. Brown, March 16, 1857.
  - Bill from unknown to Jessy Hall for $19.87, September 1857.
  - Promissory note from Jas. C. Brown from J.T. and T.R. Evins for $30.87, November 21, 1857.
  - Bill from J.T. and T.R. Evins to James Brown for coffee, sugar, calico, and nails, November 21, 1857.
  - Bill from Amiss & Callison to James Brown, November 21, 1857.
- (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Bill from Jno. M. Hinchee to James C. Brown for shoe materials, March 1, 1858.
  - Letter from J.R. Pepper in Bristol (Va.?) to his cousin Ann Barnett. Tells her of his determination to go to Louisiana, his discontent with his present situation as a doctor in Bristol, and family news, March 9, 1858.
  - Bill to James C. Brown from Younger & Smith, March 1858.
  - Bill to James C. Brown from Amiss & Callison, July 20, 1858.
  - Bill from Jas. C. Brown to John Hinchy for $15.80, January 23, 1858.
  - Bill from Jas. C. Brown to Doug Ranping(?) for $20.49, March 1, 1858.
- (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Shoemaker's bill from Jas. Collins to James Brown, November 1859.
  - Bill from Jas. M. Henderson to Jas. Brown, June 3, 1859.
  - Bill from James M. Henderson to James C. Brown for whiskey, oranges, and candy bought in 1859 and 1860, January 10, 1866.
  - Receipt for tobacco sold by Vincent Vaden of Montgomery County to James C. Brown for $200.00, September 21, 1859.
  - Bill for general merchandise bought by James C. Brown from Jno. Lybrook in 1859, July 31, 1860.
  - Court summons from the Montgomery County clerk for James C. Brown, charged with owing Abraham Crumpacker the sum of $544.65, to appear in court, April 9, 1859.
  - Court summons from the Montgomery County clerk for James Brown, charged with owing McIlvaine Sons & Co. the sum of $362.00, to appear in court July 25, 1859.
  - Various court summonses from the Montgomery County clerk for James Brown, charged with owing David K. Rankin, Adam Bruhart, J.Y. & J.R. Evans, and William Trent money, to appear in court, July 9, 1859.
  - Bill from Jones & Steptoe to J.C. Brown for bacon, sugar, and coffee, March 18, 1859.
  - Various Promissory notes from James Brown to W.H. Peck, D.K. Rankin, and William A. Heslep, February to October 1859.
  - Letter from J.R. Pepper in New Orleans to "Cousin Annie," January 25, 1859.
  - Bill from Nowlin & Mussell to Joseph Payne for cotton, wool hats, and molasses, March 17, 1859.
  - Receipt from the Virginia & Tennessee Railroad Company for $.75 paid to J.C. Brown, March 26, 1859.
  - Incomplete bill from John Hinchy to J.C. Brown (?), 1859.
  - Receipt from Joseph Ross to J.C. Brown clearing all accounts, September 29, 1859.
  - Bill from John Lybrook to James C. Brown for spoons, soap, sugar, and coffee, 1859.
- (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Receipt for F. Henderson and T.W. Brown from Jas. C. Brown for $30.40 owed to Thomas Brown's heirs, November 14, 1840 (1860?).
  - Bill from R. Calvert & Co. to James Brown for a horse collar and leather, 1860.
  - Receipt from Jacob Butt in account with J.W. Brown for tanning a deer skin, November 7, 1860.
  - Letter from Tyree & Co. in Lynchburg, Virginia, to J.C. Brown about the wholesale prices of meal, February 24, 1860.
  - Bill from James C. Brown in account with Jones & Steptoe for horseshoes, sugar, and salt, 1860.
  - Bill from Jones & Steptoe in Lynchburg, Virginia, to James C. Brown for molasses and coffee, May 23, 1860.
  - Bill from McCorkler Co. in account with James C. Brown for railroad freight and drayage, May 23, 1860.
  - Promissory note from James C. Brown to F. Henderson for $718.20, November 15, 1860.
  - Letter from William Hite to James C. Brown about a civil suit against Hite by Brown's brothers, September 30, 1860.
  - Bill from G.A. Keister to James C. Brown for sundries, November 1, 1860.
  - Letter from M.L. Dyerle to Annie Barnett asking to send the sayne gown pattern and asks her to visit soon, January 3, 1860.
  - Bill from James C. Brown in account with John M. Haney for shoes, 1860.
  - Receipt from Jas. C. Brown to Thomas W. Brown for $23.29, July 19, 1860.
  - Bill from Lybrook, Evans & Co. to James C. Brown for varnish, turpentine, putty, and sand pepper, May 9, 1860.
  - Bill from A. Ziegler to James Brown for "trimming bugge" in 1860, March 29, 1861.
  - Letter to "Dear little cousin" (Annie Barnett) from O.J.H. in Lynchburg, June 6, 1860.
  - Bill for James Brown in account with Wesley & Steward Argabright, July 27, 1860.
  - Summons from the Clerk of the Montgomery County Court for James C. Brown to appear for failing to pay Samuel W. Younger and John T. Smith the sum of $106.50, February 15, 1860.
  - Receipt from Thomas Brown for money received from Christian Kinzer, signed by Mark B. Moomaw, April 21, 1860.
  - Receipt from Henry Brown for money received from James C. Brown, February 21, 1860.
  - Receipt from W.D. Gray for money received from Jas. C. Brown, October 10, 1860.
  - Request from W.N. Gray that Jas. C. Brown pay G.D. Thomas money owed to him, September 3, 1860.
  - Bill from H.J. Henderson to James Brown for work done in 1860, February 8, 1861.
  - Letter and bill from Clarkson Anderson & Co. to J.C. Brown resettling his account, December 10, 1860.
  - General merchandise bill from Jno Obernhain to James Brown, 1860.
- (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Receipt from McCorkle & Co. to Jas. C. Brown for goods purchased in 1861, July 30, 1863.
  - "Recd. of J.C. Brown in full of Smith ac(count) by note," January 9, 1861.
  - Bill from Lybrook & Evans to James C. Brown for general merchandise, 1861.
  - Surveyor's plot written by John Tinsley for a proposed route for a road from Catawba Road to Paris Mountain; shows James Brown's house, Roanoke River, and Thomas Brown's place, February 7, 1861.
  - Summons from Montgomery County for James C.Brown to appear for failing to pay Adam Brilhart the sum of $33.11, March 2, 1861.
  - Summons from the Commonwealth of Virginia for John Brown to appear for failing to pay William Hite $544.66 in debt and $50.00 in damages, January 21, 1861.
  - Summons from the Commonwealth of Virgina for Thomas W., James C., and John Brown to appear for failing to pay $544.66 to William Hite, January 21, 1861.
  - County War Tax receipt on a printed form for James C. Brown. The receipt shows 1 white and 2 black tithes ($4.50), County War Tax (land $7.43, property $.85) totaling $8.28, State tax on property and value ($6.62) and 297 acres of land ($29.71) all totaling $49.11, 1861.
  - Letter from J. W. D------ to Miss Ann about his trip from Craney Island, August 10, 1861.
  - Promissory note to John M. Haning from Jas C. Brown for $19.00, October 19, 1861.
  - Promissory note to H. Black from Jas C. Brown for $75.50, March 29, 1861.
  - Promissory note to J. B. Fulw----- from J. -- Brown for $3.40, January 19, 1861.
  - Note saying that Wesley Augerbright owes Jas C. Brown $10.00 for 10 bushels of wheat, October 16, 1861.
  - Bill to James C. Brown from George Gallion for making a coffin and for liquor. The payment for the bill was received on 6 September, 1861.
  - Written account from William Henderson about Jas C. Brown working off an account, 1861.
- (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Handwritten valentine from S. M. W. with original verse, 1862.
  - Bill from William Smith to Jas C. Brown for 6 bushels of rye for $7.20, February 5, 1862.